<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pranav Madhikar</title>
    <description>Pranav Madhikar&#39;s blog. Come here to see all of Pranav&#39;s musings, rants, and general wastes of time. 
</description>
    <link>http://madhikar.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://madhikar.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2017 21:30:03 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2017 21:30:03 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to do a PhD</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So you’re thinking of doing a PhD? Well, you’ve come to the right
place for advice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;its-easy-just-follow-these-steps&quot;&gt;It’s easy just follow these steps:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Learn how to read flowcharts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Follow this flowchart:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/phdhowto/phdhowto.png&quot; alt=&quot;Awesome Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol start=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Learn how to write flowcharts. There is a lot of internet money in it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://madhikar.com/therapy/2017/07/02/phd-howto.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://madhikar.com/therapy/2017/07/02/phd-howto.html</guid>
        
        <category>Self Help</category>
        
        <category>Passing Wisdom</category>
        
        <category>Skin</category>
        
        
        <category>Therapy</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Mountain of Knowledge</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Mountain of knowledge stands tall, immovable. It is the greatest
of all. Its influence is undeniable and its structure imposing. Only
the greatest dare to climb it. And when they do, they return humbled,
silent. I have seen the Mountain and felt its shade. I journeyed the
lands to tell all of its greatness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found the builder, building a castle. The builder received me
courteously, covered in sweat and dust. Grasping a hammer in one hand,
and an stone in another. I told the builder, “The Mountain of
knowledge inspires your design, it provides you material to
build. You’re castle is quite great Builder, but it cannot compete
with the grandeur of the Mountain. The Mountain is wisest of
all”. “Yes”, the builder agreed, “surely”, and gazed at the Mountain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found the leader, seated on a throne. Chosen by the people, with
undeniable authority. The leader sat in fine clothes, atop a golden
seat, at the end of the great hall. Grasping a gavel in one hand, and
a sword in the other. I told the leader, “The Mountain of Knowledge
cannot be conquered. It governs you, the governor. And it is the
source of your power. Your wisdom is quite great Leader, but it cannot
compete with the Mountain. The Mountain is greatest of all”. “Yes”,
the leader agreed, “surely”, and gazed at the Mountain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found the painter, standing in front of an easel, In deep
contemplation. Contemplating the natural and the artificial. The
artist held a brush in one hand, and a key in the other. I told the
painter, “The Mountain of Knowledge is the source of your
creativity. From atop it you see your vistas. Your paintings are
beautiful Painter, but they cannot compete with the beauty of the
Mountain. The Mountain is the most beautiful of all”. “Yes”, the
painter agreed, “surely”, and gazed at the Mountain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I found the Jester, performing in front of an
audience. Holding a lyre in one hand and a mask in the other. Master
of sight, sound, and emotion. “The Mountain of Knowledge is the source
of your insight into the human soul. Its slopes defy even your best
melodies. Your performance is dazzling Jester, but you cannot compete
with the presence of the mountain”. The Jester looked at me and smiled
and said, “The Mountain makes the mind myopic. It sublimely surrounds
sight, lecherously limits light, brazenly bellows blight. Walk wearily
when wandering within its wake. The peak’s power is princely and pure,
possibly. However humanity is half harrowing, half helpful. All
abilities abuse as well as aid. It is, therefore, only a
transfigurable tool. Ascend it for insight, mine it for might, or leap
upon it for light. Unconscious use utterly usurps the faculties, of
friend and of foe. Viewpoint, volition, or vagueness can vary
veracity, villify the virtuous, vouch for the vile.” The jester turned
to the mountain and held up a finger and a thumb. “Make the mightiest
mountain a mote.” The Jester smiled and raised a smug eyebrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have never understood the Jester. Were the world to be united on one
side, then the Jester will stand on the other. For nothing more than a
matter of principle. Is dissent for its own sake justifiable? Must all
truth be eternally questioned? A fact is not beholden to
interpretation. I had gazed at the steep slopes of the Mountain. I had
marvelled at its enourmous height. I had witnessed the truth, and the
truth had witnessed me. There is nothing greater. I would show the
Jester the failings of doubt. “Look up you imbecile!”, I begged the
Jester. “Gaze up and acknowledge that greatness.”  The Jester smiled
and said, “Indeed, I am an imbecile.”  and returned to the
performance. What does this fool know of anything?  Nothing. The
jester’s purpose is to perform. This was nothing more than just a
performance. I would prove truth true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Mountain stood tall. All roads lead to it. And all roads come from
it. I would walk the path up the Mountain. I would look down from its
peak. And all of creation will gaze up to me as it’s better. Including
the damned Jester. Determined, I made haste to the foot of the
Mountain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The size of the Mountain is immense, yet it grew as I approached it. I
walked on, unfazed by its expanding slopes. The Mountain’s surface,
once smooth and youthful from a distance, resolved itself into
roughness. Grizzled with the tips of trees, gouged with deep creases
that cut across jaggedly. But where is the path to its peak? I could
not see how to climb the treacherous face of the Mountain. Darkness
was descending, I had to find shelter. There was a single hut near the
foot of the Mountain. Determined, I made haste to the hut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within was an hermit, seated at a fire, sipping from a cup. The hermit
jerked up and stared suspiciously with deep brown eyes. It was as if
those eyes gazed into my soul. “Who the hell are you?”, snapped the
hermit with a voice that sounded like it belonged to a much younger
person, yet it was filled with confidence and authority. “I am here to
climb the Mountain”, I said with as much poise as I could
muster. “Well, of course you are here to climb The Mountain. I want to
know who you are”, croaked the Hermit. “It does not matter, I must
climb to the top.” The Hermit looked at me curiously, “Why? Climbing
The Mountain is no easy task. It might take ten years, more if you are
not determined. Did you see how it grew as you approached it? That
never stops. The Mountain keep grows beneath your feet even as you
stand upon it. Why must you go to the peak?”. I was shocked! What new
arrogance was this? “I do not have to explain myself to you, Hermit!
Is it not enough that I want to do it?” I spat. Defeated, the Hermit
sighed and said, “Very well, follow me.” And walked out of the
hut. Determined, I made haste behind the Hermit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The Mountain is not something to be conquered, that is not possible,”
said the Hermit, not caring whether I listened or not. “No one has
been to the peak. It is unclear whether a peak even exists. There are
many, perhaps innumerable, paths of The Mountain. Dense, winding, and
interconnected. I once had a friend how was climbing up the northern
face, and surprisingly ended up making a level path along the eastern
ridge! It was most surpr—”, the Hermit droned on and on. the stream
of information was never ending, but I’d had enough. “What do you mean
there are innumerable paths? I see none.” Annoyed at being
interrupted, the Hermit looked back and said, “Well of course you
don’t see any paths. You must first climb the Stairs, only then will
you be able to see the paths. Now shut up and listen!” The Hermit
grasped my arm and thrust me forward. “Look there,” said the Hermit,
pointing to side of the rising slopes. “Those are the endless
Stairs. Only when you have climbed them all and carve a new step at
the top, will you be able to scale the rest of The Mountain. You must
first stand upon the work of all of those who came before you. Only
then, will you see how to climb The Mountain. Not everyone is capable
of doing this of course. But that is okay, there are some paths that
lead away from the Stairs laterally. You may take those paths and be
equally renowned. But the so-called peak is at the top, so those only
interested in the top”, the disdain in the Hermit’s tone was palpable,
“must go to the top of the Stairs”. I was confused, “What do you mean
endless Stairs? if they are endless how am I supposed to go to the
top?”. Now the Hermit now smiled and said, “They are endless because
they grow as well, many have come before you and every single person
that has climbed them has added a new step. Some have added
several. In fact, some steps are being added as we speak!” This was
strange, how would I be able to reach the peak if the stairs keep
growing? Determined, I made haste to the stairs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://madhikar.com/lame%20writing/2017/05/02/the-mountain-of-knowledge.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://madhikar.com/lame%20writing/2017/05/02/the-mountain-of-knowledge.html</guid>
        
        <category>Learning</category>
        
        <category>Short Story</category>
        
        <category>Fable</category>
        
        
        <category>Lame Writing</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Martin Tyepni: Prologue</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Last edited 02-05-2017&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;The biography of the great warrior, and leader among all races. The
chosen by divinity. The wielder of wrath, light, and vengeance, Martin
Tyepni.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;color:#8A0707&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The singly testicled. The sometimes sober. The conquerer of women…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center; font-size: 20&quot;&gt;a book by Martin Tyepni&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;color:#8A0707&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;So you want to learn about me? Well, you are going to regret that
decision my friend. Prepare your body, I know mine is ;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;color:#8A0707&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;This copy is annotated with some color commentary done by yours
truly. You’re welcome.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would like to start this biography by providing a small introduction
to my city. I think this is needed to provide some context for my
story. The rest of the book will be written from a narrators
perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;color:#8A0707&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Probably best to let the voices in my head out this way.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-brief-history-of-the-great-city-of-tandor&quot;&gt;A Brief History of The Great City of Tandor&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Far in the north across the sea, in the icy continent of Tan, in the
middle of an almost straight edge between the sea to the south and icy
wastes to the north lies the great city of Tandor. It is said that
once long ago, perhaps when the old empire still reigned, Tandor was a
simple fishing village. Over the centuries since the fall of the
empire, Tandor would grow into one of two major strongholds in the
north. In this chapter, I will try to give a brief summary of Tandoran
history. Wherever necessary, I have citations to other sources of
information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;color:#8A0707&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Didn’t expect me to be so eloquent in my writing did you? I’ll have
you know that my education was, according to my father, “paramount to
the future function, safety, and economy of the great city of
Tandor”. I had to stuff my head with words and facts. My mediocre
writing is the only thing I choose to remember.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fishing village mostly housed five or six families of peasants
that were forced there due to struggles within the empire. It isn’t
apparent whether the village was named Tandor during those
times. Recorded Tandoran history goes only as far back as one name:
Bolard Jadr the founder of the Jadr fishing company. Historians still
debate if Bolard is the one to have named the village Tandor. All that
can be proved is that Tandor was the only settlement in Tan at the
time. So it is not unreasonable for the locals to have simply named it
after the continent Tan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jadr had once been a soldier in a great army, or so he claimed. It is
unclear what wars he fought or which lord he served. He was, most
likely, a middling soldier in the armies of one of the lords vying for
power after the fall of the old empire. Given the lack of records of
his service, it is very probably that he fought for one of the lords
that lost. Victors decide historical truth afterall. Jadr was not
known to have been well educated or particularly intelligent. There
isn’t any evidence that he knew anything about fishing either. What he
did have was a large sum of gold that he had acquired in “an
inheritance from a distant relative”. Running a fishing business can
be quite simple especially when labor is cheap and competition
non-existent—as was the case in Tandor. The Tanian coast is home to
a particular sort of crab that only grows there. The delicious flesh
inside the icy crab shells were highly sought after over the whole
world, but none would brave the cold to catch them. Jadr had no
problem paying some starving peasants to catch them and then paying
other starving peasants to ship them. The peasants, for their part,
were happy to work for fair wages. The Jadr fishing company became the
sole mass supplier of the crab-meat to the whole world. And Bolard
became mayor of Tandor. Later the same kind of crab was named the
Tandoran frost crab. The baked delicacy made of the crabs flesh,
simply called “Jadr’s bake”, can be found only at the most lavish
tables. Named after the brand on the barrels that the meat was shipped
in. Jadr took all the gold that he made selling crab and placed into a
number of highly lucrative business ventures. Somehow, Jadr proved to
be a shrewd businessman. Most soldiers spent what little money they
made on drinking, gambling, and women. And Jadr indulged in all three
heavily, yet he seemed to always be making much more gold than he
spent. Whatever his vices, he had one quality that most definitely
made Tandor into the city that it is today. He was not particularly
selfish. Jadr was perfectly content with letting others get rich as
long as they made him richer. Thanks to this attitude, many traders
from around the rest of the world traveled to Tandor to trade. And
some even stayed permanently. The first few years of Jadr’s time as
mayor saw a huge growth in Tandor. Those that were once peasants
became as rich as nobility essentially overnight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;color:#8A0707&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Why the fuck would traders leave their warm marble houses filled with
wine, food, and whores? And why would they bury themselves into the
icy butt crack of the world? Well, even though Jadr didn’t know much
about history, geography, trade, or anything. He did know one thing:
Traders don’t like to pay tax. So he made Tandor the only tax free
town in the world. No king was stupid enough to try and conquer the
north. And when the traders did go back to their fancy houses, they
brought back plenty of lining for the royal coffers. Tandor was mostly
left alone. The tax free markets in Tandor didn’t last that long
though. At some point tax became mandatory, but that was after Tandor
had already become a major center of trade and the Tandoran council
was established. The tax was still the lowest back then. It still is
now.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One may wonder why the powerful kings of the south never tried to
conquer Tan after the dust of the fall of the empire had settled. The
Tanian climate is probably the most hostile known. The winters are
brutally cold and dry, the summers only slightly less so. There is
very little land amenable to farming. Before Tandor, no settlement had
lasted very long in the icy wastes. The inhospitable nature of Tan was
not the only thing that kept it unsettled by the noble races&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Many
of the ancient, almost forgotten beasts of the world moved north to
avoid the explosion of civilization in the temperate continents during
the past two or three millenia. A cursory reading of imperial history
will reveal many reports of early Tanian settlements completely
disappearing and entire armies being driven mad before starving, then
freezing. The trick, it seems, was to hug the coast as Tandor does
today. Another theory is that the time of the ancient monstrous beings
ended at roughly the same time the empire fell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;color:#8A0707&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Who knows? Tandor and Jadr were probably just founded in the right
place at the right time. Nothing has gone wrong yet. My mother would
tell me stories about the ancient beings that lived far in the
north. That was probably just to make me read my books though.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever the fate of the ancient ones, there has always been a
presence of semi-intelligent ice giants, frost wolves, the occasional
ice dragon, and an uncountable amount of other beasts that roamed the
frost planes.  The large numbers, and uncommon ferocity of the
Tanian native beasts combined with the relative lack of natural
resources effectively kept any plans of settling Tan or conquering
Tandor at bay. The rich kings and emperors of the other continents
were content to fight over land that could actually be fought
on. While this kept the little town of Tandor safe from conquest,
there was still the constant threat of the beasts that roamed the
frost planes, piracy that plagued the trade ships that sailed to and
from Tandor, and the rise of crime in the town itself. The Jadr
company recognized these threats as particularly harmful to its
commercial activities but it struggled to stop them for many
years. The mercenaries that Bolard Jadr hired to protect Tandor were
unreliable. The lives of all Tandorans were at near constant
risk. This was one of the few periods of Tandoran history when trade
declined. The other major ones were the decades long Tanian war&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;,
and the frost famine&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;color:#8A0707&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tandor had just turned into a shiny jewel, and all kinds of riff-raff
came around to steal it away from Old Bolard Jadr. He had no idea how
to fight all the giants, wolves, and criminals invading Tandor. He
could swing a sword only about as well as he could swing his dick. He
was no leader of soldiers. He needed help to protect his town. That’s
where my family comes in.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To combat these problems, Jadr made a crucial decision that would
shape the future of Tandor for generations to come. He formed the
Tandoran city guard. The new guard would as much part of Tandor as
Bolard Jadr himself, and the Tandoran people. Thus far the Jadr
fishing company relied on mercenaries to guard Tandor. This quickly
proved to be short sighted. The mercenaries were more interested in
making gold than protecting Tandor. Jadr needed someone with a deep
sense of honor and justice to keep watch over Tandor. In what at the
time seemed as a surprising lack of creativity on Jadr’s part, Jadr
turned to his old captain, a man by the name of Simon Tyepni. Not much
of Simon Tyepni’s, later entitled the leviathan of Tandor&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:4&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:4&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, history
is known. Tyepni was a captain of the small company of soldiers that
Jadr served in. Like Bolard Jadr, no records of Captain Tyepni that
predate his time in Tandor exist. What little information known about
him is from the biography of Bolard Jadr himself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“During all my time in battle, Captain Tyepni was the only person would
cared about my well being. His extraordinary skills in battle and his
ability to form unbeatable strategies even in the heat of a losing
war instilled in me a sense of loyalty that I did not know I was
capable of. Whatever the outcome of that war, I would follow him
anywhere.”&lt;/em&gt; Excerpt from “Force of Will and a Small Amount of Luck”,
by Bolard Jadr.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the Jadr company was still making a name for itself, Tyepni had
formed a group of mercenaries the like of which never existed before
and will probably never exist again. One that never betrayed its
patrons. Tyepni’s mercenaries were known as the only group that would
always serve their charge until the end of their contracts no matter
what price they were offered to break it or how many lives they lost
for it. Furthermore, they had yet to fail a contract. This was
precisely the kind of soldiers that Jadr was looking for. Luckily,
Simon Tyepni was getting tired of fighting for the sake of gold
alone. He was looking for a home to fight for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along with him, Tyepni brought a group of elite soldiers trained by
Tyepni himself. These soldiers proved to be exactly what Tandor
needed. Resolved to follow Tyepni to the death and determined to
protect Tandor. Some attribute this extreme sense of loyalty and duty
to the extraordinary leadership skills of Simon Tyepni. Many landless
warriors from around the world moved to Tandor to serve under him
after hearing about his extraordinary battle prowess, tactical acumen,
and the promise of a home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;color:#8A0707&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Yup, Tyepnis are badass.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jadr and Tyepni made an agreement that included land and housing for
the Tandoran guard to be. This effectively made the mercenaries
citizens of Tandor, who quickly began to settle down and start
families. Under the watchful gaze of Simon Tyepni and his city
guard. Tandor quickly became relatively safe. Once reassured, the
skittish traders that had earlier fled returned in droves. And many
new ones came to stay. In some of the greatest sea battles of the
time, Tyepni and his Tandoran guard almost eliminated the threat of
piracy that plagued the northern trade routes. Tyepni himself slew the
fearsome pirate simply known as The Yellow Woman. After their
legendary combat, the Tandorans gave Simon Tyepni the title of The
Leviathan of Tandor. Leviathan became the title of the general of the
Tandoran guard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now secure from threats to its safety, Tandor boomed once again. The
little town that Jadr oversaw was quickly becoming too much for him to
handle on his own. No official form of government was needed to rule
the tiny Tandoran populace so far. It had now become too large to be
managed by a single person. Jadr himself was not that interested in
political power, all he wanted to was to make more gold and do so
while getting fat in his palace. Together with the first Leviathan,
Jadr formed the first Tandoran council. This council would be made of
representatives of the three pillars of Tandor. The Jadr fishing
company&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:5&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:5&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, the Tandoran guard, and the Tandoran people. The three
council members were (and still are to this day) named, Master of the
Jadr fishing company, The Leviathan of Tandor, and the high councilor
of Tandor, selected by the people. These three leaders represented the
economic, military, and social interests of Tandor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;color:#8A0707&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;A new city was born. The first one without a king! The councilor was
“chosen by the people”. This basically meant the richest in Tandor got
to choose who led the city. The poor are basically fucked over. They
aren’t educated well enough to realize what is going on. Luckily,
the Leviathans were normally looking out for the poor. Where else
would they find new recruits for the guard?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hundreds of years later we come to modern Tandor. The Tandoran
military is unrivaled in skill, but relatively small since it only
guards one city. What they lack in size they more than make up for in
quality. Thankfully the large amount of trade links that Tandor
maintains with the rest of the world keeps it in good diplomatic
relationships with most kingdoms. People of all races are welcome in
Tandor. Modern Tandor is one of the most diverse cities in the
world. All Leviathans have been human, however. The fact that
Leviathan is only chosen from a pool of candidates keeps any concerns
of nepotism at bay. Despite this, all leviathans have been descendants
of Simon Tyepni who seem to have some elvish in them. The most
lacking aspect of Tandor is its relatively small contribution to the
arcane arts. And most of the kingdoms in the south are dismissive of
its military strength. In effect, the harsh environment is a
significant part of security against threats to the sovereignty of the
Tandoran council.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;color:#8A0707&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;A lot of half and half people live there. One of two half-orcs that I
have ever known lived there.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tandor remains neutral in all wars that do not threaten its own
security. Even the elven enclave that was on the other side in the
great Tanian war is now one of the greatest trade partners of
Tandor. In fact, every year there is an exchange of dignitaries
between Tandor and the elves to commemorate the meeting between the
3rd Leviathan of Tandor and the then elven general that ended the
bloody war between the two cities. Now, both cites enjoy a robust
diplomatic relationship, even though the elves seem to only engage
with Tandor begrudgingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;color:#8A0707&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;One of these meetings would change my life forever. I probably would
never lost my right testicle if it wasn’t for that damned woman.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I, Martin Tyepni, was born to Garlan Tyepni the 7th Leviathan, 67
years ago in the city of Tandor. I was the eldest son to the 7th
Leviathan and was educated and trained to become the next one. Though,
as fate would have it, the divine had other plans for me. Now that the
roots of my city have been described, we can move on to my own story,
in later chapters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;other-sources-and-notes&quot;&gt;Other Sources and Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;color:#8A0707&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Well what did you expect? Learn something for a change.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Needless to say, the term “noble races” is clearly a
misnomer. There isn’t necessarily anything noble about them. In
the widely read and accepted work of the Ezarian historian Alijn
Yuolark “A Treatise on our Origins”. The author names all those
races that have developed civilizations, “noble races”. These not
only include the highly evolved races such as elves, humans,
gnomes, dragonborn, etc, but also goblins, gnolls, orcs, etc. All
other animals are named the “ignoble races”. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;This war was a protracted conflict with a newly formed elven
enclave to the east of Tandor. See the biography of the great
Tandoran general Jerald Tyepni, 3rd leviathan, titled “Ice, Glory,
and the Folly of War” for a detailed account of those events. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:3&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;The aforementioned lack of farmable land caused this
problem. Fortunately, many Gnomish Tandoran citizens were trying
to find ways of growing food indoors that required a great deal of
ingenuity. Their tireless work culminated in the invention of the
great Tandoran green houses. The science behind them is the only
thing not for sale in Tandor. High material and magical cost
of running them and the fact that most people live near or on
farmland keeps the southern kings uninterested in this
technology. The high cost of food in Tandor keeps the population
from growing very fast. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:4&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Leviathan later became the official title of the general of the
Tandoran guard. It was passed down to later leaders of the guard,
which were almost invariably descendants of Simon Tyepni. Until
the defiance of Martin Tyepni, who was the 8th leviathan in training
until his marriage. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:4&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:5&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;In modern times, the name “Jadr fishing company” is only used
for historic reasons. Fishing is only a small component of its
operations in modern times. It is also no longer a company per se,
but the financial arm of the Tandoran government. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:5&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://madhikar.com/lame%20writing/2016/08/08/martin-chapter1.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://madhikar.com/lame%20writing/2016/08/08/martin-chapter1.html</guid>
        
        <category>Back story</category>
        
        <category>Fantasy</category>
        
        <category>D&amp;D</category>
        
        <category>Martin</category>
        
        
        <category>Lame Writing</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hello World?</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-problems-with-blogs&quot;&gt;The Problems with Blogs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past few years, I have created about three blogs, if you can call them that.
It would be more accurate to say that they were attempts at starting blogs.
Unfortunately those things always remained lifeless. Even attempting them was
a huge waste of time. For me and for whatever poor soul decided to read it.
So, you have been warned, don’t expect much over here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that your expectations have been lowered, let’s get rid of dreary disclaimers,
and move onto to boring content. The main reason behind my lack of blogging was
a normally non-reliable internet connection in my house. This was mostly due to
the fact that I was living in Egypt. And even though internet connections have
always been a thing in Egypt since the early 90s, people didn’t really embrace
it until sometime at the beginning of the 00s. Egyptian kids my age didn’t really
get online much until Facebook came around. I never really thought I needed a
fast internet connection so I didn’t push my parents to get one. We did have
dialup which seemed enough at the time since it fullfilled most of our needs.
We never got a reliable internet connection until about 2008 (yes, 2008) when I
moved to Canada for school and we needed to use Skype. Since then, my family has
caught up with the rest of the world. I’m happy to say that my family has developed
a good addiction to the internet. Which means I can’t use crappy internet as an
excuse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first blog post ever was sometime in 2005 on blogger. Nothing came out of
that, mostly because the internet issue but partially also because I didn’t have
much to say at the time. As anybody reading this can see, that is still something
I struggle with until now. I later tried out tumblr, no dice. Thinking that I
might have at least 140 characters worth, I got on twitter. Still nothing. I guess
I’m just not the most interesting person. I’ve just spent all this time convincing
you that I’m not good at blogging. So what is happening here? Another exercise in
futility? Maybe –probably– though I hope not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve decided that the reason why I didn’t end up writing much of anything is that
I couldn’t control the content of my blog fully. As far as I know, free accounts
on tumblr, blogger, wordpress, etc. don’t offer much customizability. I like to
be able to to control how things appear. Of course, this can be done by buying some
hosting somewhere and hosting your own website. But that is too much work. You
see I wanted to do everything by myself but I didn’t want to do &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt;
by myself. This included things like setting up something like a wordpress instance
which involves a whole bunch of web development crap, and learning html and js.
I did try to do these things, but I’m just not smart enough to quickly learn all
these things quickly and build a website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I continued quietly chastise myself for being cheap and a little
lazy, and resumed my blogless existence. Some time ago, about six months before
this post I think, I started to come accross quite a few solutions around that
were catering to people like me. Things like flask, jekyll, or ruhoh. These are
all great, but we still have the hosting problem. Can’t a guy reach an audience
of potentially millions for free? Well, thanks to github, a guy now can. Using
&lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllbootstrap.com/&quot;&gt;jekyll-bootstrap&lt;/a&gt;. I don’t know how it works, but
it does, so here I am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ever since a young age, I have been interested in writing. Once upon a time, I
fancied myself a literary genius. I’ve since learnt that I am quite the opposite, a
literary dunce. My goal with this blog is to scratch that creative itch. I have
to write quite a few scientific reports for school and work. It’s not like I
don’t write at all. But writing something is easy, making it interesting and
understandable to a wide audience is an art. An art I would like to learn. I
will try to write as much as possible here to that end. Somebody might find it
interesting, but this blog will be mostly for me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://madhikar.com/rants/2015/07/03/hello-world.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://madhikar.com/rants/2015/07/03/hello-world.html</guid>
        
        <category>misc</category>
        
        
        <category>Rants</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
